A hot spot in a cold war.
The Atomic Cafe is a documentary, history film directed by Jayne Loader.
A disturbing collection of 1940s and 1950s United States government-issued propaganda films
designed to reassure Americans that the atomic bomb was not a threat to their safety.
Self (archive footage), played by Harry S. Truman.
Self (archive footage), played by Lyndon B. Johnson.
Self (archive footage), played by Nikita Khrushchev.
Self (archive footage), played by Lewis Strauss.
Self (archive footage), played by Julius Rosenberg.
Self (archive footage), played by Ethel Rosenberg.
The Atomic Cafe is a 1982 American documentary film directed by
Kevin Rafferty, Jayne Loader and Pierce Rafferty.
It is a compilation of clips from newsreels, military training films, and other footage produced
in the United States early in the Cold War on the subject of nuclear warfare.
Without any narration, the footage is edited and presented in a manner to
demonstrate how misinformation and propaganda was used by the U.S.
government and popular culture to ease fears about
nuclear weapons among the American public.
In 2016, the film was selected  for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant."
The film explores themes of nuclear war, propaganda,
atomic bomb, cold war, advertising.
The tone is dark.